http://www.rdansw.org.au/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy
Policy Preamble
Riding for the Disabled Association (NSW) – RDA (NSW) – collects and administers a range of personal and health information required for the primary activities of the organisation.
RDA (NSW) is committed to maintaining the privacy and confidentiality of the information it collects, holds and administers. RDA (NSW) complies with the Privacy Act 1988 including the 13 Australian Privacy Principles (APPs) as outlined in the Privacy Amendment (Enhancing Privacy Protection) Act 2012.
We recognise the rights of individuals to have their information administered in ways they would reasonably expect – protected on the one hand and made accessible to them on the other. These privacy values are reflected in and supported by our core values and philosophies.
We manage personal information in an open and transparent way. This is evident in the implementation of practices, procedures and systems we outline in this policy, that ensure our compliance with the Australian Privacy Principles and any binding registered Australian Privacy Principles code, and provide suitable procedures for RDA (NSW) personnel to be able to deal with related inquiries and complaints that may be received from time to time.
RDA (NSW) will:
• Collect only information which the organisation requires for its primary functions;
• Ensure participants are informed as to why we collect and how we administer the information gathered;
• Use and disclose the personal information only for our primary functions or a directly related purpose, or for another purpose with the person’s consent;
• Store personal information securely, protecting it from unauthorised access; and
• Provide participants with access to their own information and the right to seek its correction.
Objectives
The objectives of RDA (NSW)’s Privacy Policy are to:
Ensure information is received, recorded, accessed and stored appropriately to maintain confidentiality.
Remain compliant with:
• The Privacy Act 1988 (as amended);
• Government body funding agreements as well as accreditation and licensing standards;
• All relevant legislation; and
• Any other RDA (NSW) Policies and Procedures related to the collection, storage or other use of Personal Information including on written application from participant or carer transferring participant Participation/Medical Form to another Centre.
Ensure that all participants are aware of their rights in regards to privacy and confidentiality and are aware of the means to access or amend private information held about them; and
Ensure that any Personal Information collected is directly related to RDA (NSW) service functions or activities.
Definitions
“Personal Information” means information or an opinion (including information or an opinion held in a database), whether true or not, and whether recorded in a material form or not, about an individual whose identity is apparent, or can reasonably be ascertained, from the information or opinion.
“Health Information” is information or an opinion about:
• the physical, mental or psychological health (at any time) of an individual;
• a disability (at any time) of an individual; or
• an individual’s expressed wishes about the future provision of health services to him or her.
